<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emma's Website and Blog</title>
    <link>https://emmasax4.info</link>
    <atom:link href="https://emmasax4.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Skimp and Splurge</title>
        
          <subtitle>Part 3: From Others' Perspectives</subtitle>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my intentions for the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/skimp-and-splurge/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Skimp and Splurge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; blog collection is that it can be used by young adults to help them figure out which items are important for them to fit into their budget. I want my readers to understand that for every person, what they prioritize in their budget is personal, and what I find valuable, somebody else may not want or need in their budget. Therefore, I knew it’d be important to get some other folks’ opinions on each of these topics, so that my readers have more data to parse and more opinions for them to base their choices on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, like any good blogger, I conducted interviews. I intended to interview around five people for this post, but I ended up only getting two. So, the post won’t be quite as long as originally intended, but it’ll still suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-skimp-daily-coffee&quot;&gt;1. SKIMP: daily coffee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to drink coffee daily, then you &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; need to own your own coffeemaker. No ifs, ands, or buts. Preferably, you should own a basic one that will make a pot of coffee at a time (instead of single-serving cups), because they’ll be a better investment when buying coffee beans and when serving a group of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even better, if your work serves free coffee (like mine does), then take advantage of that and just bring your own cream and sugar as necessary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-splurge-apartment-rent&quot;&gt;2. SPLURGE: apartment rent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the unanimous decision of the group was that location is everything. Whether that means location within a safe neighborhood, proximity to work, location within walkable distance to grocery stores and restaurants, whatever it is you prioritize. I know people that happily live in downtown Minneapolis so that they can walk to a bunch of yummy restaurants. For me, the idea of having to be in that traffic and noise every day stresses me out, so I happily live in the suburbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other constant requirements was air conditioning (preferrably, central air), and that there was available laundry in the building. For me, that escalates to laundry on my floor (stairs to do laundry is an annoyance of college-era).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-skimp-tons-of-new-clothes&quot;&gt;3. SKIMP: tons of new clothes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I described this to my interviewees is that there’s three ways to buy clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy cheap clothes in higher quantity: you’ll have plenty of clothes, but they’ll wear out faster so they will soon need replacement by other cheap clothes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy more expensive clothes in lower quantity: they’ll last longer, but you won’t have as many items in your closet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy higher quality clothes used at a discount: they won’t be the newest fashion or &quot;in-season&quot;, and they may not fit perfectly, but they’ll last a while, and they’ll save you some cash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my interviewees opted for the third option. The other interviewee opted for the second option. The reason for choosing the third option is that you can have a closet with more options for outfits, without sacrificing the quality of the clothing. Makes sense. The reasoning for choosing the second option is for somebody that maybe doesn’t need a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of suits in the closet, only one or two. Get decent quality of them even if they were more expensive, so that you don’t need to replace them every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole group agreed that purchasing cheap clothes that are crappy quality usually is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; worth it in the grand scheme of things. Clothes that you buy should last more than a year. If they’re not lasting that long, then they’re poor quality, and it’s worth it to either shop at thrift stores or shell out a few more bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t take into account the sector of the population that cannot afford to pay a bit more for better quality clothing. If you fall into that group, I’d highly suggest going with the third option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-splurge-eating-at-nice-restaurants&quot;&gt;4. SPLURGE: eating at nice restaurants&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general opinion of this topic is that it’s totally ok to eat out at nice restaurants, perhaps even good for people, if it only happens rarely, perhaps once a month. Sometimes, it’d good to treat yourself to a nice dinner with your SO. Just make sure it’s not happening on a weekly or daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-skimp-tons-of-takeout-and-fast-food&quot;&gt;5. SKIMP: tons of takeout and fast-food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overwhelming opinion of this topic is to skimp, skimp, and &lt;em&gt;skimp&lt;/em&gt;! If you don’t want to cook a meal, then you might as well eat good quality food and have somebody serve it to your table. Unless you’re actually in a rush and need the &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;-food. But for the most part, you should cook at home for healtier and most cost-effective meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-splurge-video-streaming-servies&quot;&gt;6. SPLURGE: video streaming servies*&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opinion here is that for most people, it is nice to have at least one video streaming service. We even all agree that it’s nice to have more than one. But, it’s important to do your research. Only get the streaming services that you feel like you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want. Are you getting the streaming service to watch 10 shows and/or movies, or just for that one show that you’re interested in? If you’re in the latter boat, then maybe ask your friends and/or family if they already have accounts that you can use (make sure to offer to pay them a couple bucks a month if they give you their login information).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think carefully whether shelling out an extra $6/month is worth it to go ad-free. Especially if you only want to watch a couple of things on that service, it’s probably not necessary to get rid of ads. Similarly consider how many screens you really need to buy. If the account is just for you and SO, then you probably really only need two screens. If it’s for a whole family, then maybe four is worth it. Also, do you really need 4K definition, or is HD enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest thing we can stress is that at some point, you’ve got to pick and choose which streaming services you think paying money for is worth. For me, I’m guessing that Disney+ will always be worth it. And perhaps either Hulu or Netflix, but probably not both. But getting ESPN bundled with Hulu and Disney+ isn’t worth that money, just because I’ll never use ESPN. But if I already have Amazon Prime for fast shipping, then I might as well take advantage of their video content as well, instead of paying for yet another video streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just always do your research, and make sure to ask friends/family if they have accounts they’d be willing to let you use. Take it from me: using a friends account is the &lt;em&gt;cheapest&lt;/em&gt; way to get content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-skimp-expensive-phone-bills-with-tons-of-unused-data&quot;&gt;7. SKIMP: expensive phone bills with tons of unused data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interviewees stressed that whether this is a Skimp or a Splurge depends on what the use of this bill is. If it’s your only source of internet, aka you don’t have WiFi, then this is probably a Splurge so that you can do whatever you need to do on your phone or with a hotspot. If you’re just a single person who uses WiFi most of the time, then use a pay-as-you-go plan so you’re not overpaying. But if you’re purchasing a phone plan for a whole family, then getting unlimited data for the whole family may be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that our audience for these posts is a new graduate with not a lot of monthly income, then my suggestion is to either use a pay-as-you-go plan, or try to share a phone plan with your roommates, friends, or SO (or your parents), and then share the cost of unlimited data for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-splurge-a-good-car&quot;&gt;8. SPLURGE: a good car&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agreement here is that safety is the number one priority when choosing a mode of transportation. Especially in Minnesota winters, you need a car that can get you from point A to point B even in the snowiest weather. But, I understand that getting a top rated car costs money that young adults may not have laying around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, I’d say go carless for a while. Try to live in an area that has a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.walkscore.com/MN/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;walking and biking score&lt;/a&gt;, and get a bus pass. If you have roommates or SOs that you live with, try to share a car while you save up money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that isn’t possible and you absolutely need a car, then next try to look for friends or family members that may have a car that you can purchase from them for a discount. I know several people that have gotten hand-me-down vehicles from grandparents, aunts, and uncles at a significant discount. OR, they got a cheap car that wasn’t that safe, but then traded it in at the dealers to get a discount on a nicer car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, buy used cars! I’ve noticed from friends that buying a new car typically isn’t worth it unless you want the newest safety features or addons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-skimp-buying-a-couch-right-when-i-move-out&quot;&gt;9. SKIMP: buying a couch right when I move out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, all of my interviewees wanted to move this category from a Skimp to a Splurge! They all agree that it’s nice to have a place to sit that’s not a floor or a bed (maybe that mentality is part of the college-era, too). But, they did stress that it doesn’t need to be a nice couch. It can be a $500 Ikea couch, or a nice leather couch from a thrift store. If it’s not too dirty, it could also just be your roommates couch that they brought from their parents’ house. In general, I’d highly recommend taking some furniture from your parents’ basement, if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-splurge-a-good-bed&quot;&gt;10. SPLURGE: a good bed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consensus on the bed is that a good bed is a must. The mattress doesn’t have to be super fancy, and you don’t need to get a nice bed frame with a headboard and footboard. But you should get a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; mattress (they’ll be cleaner and better quality… also ew!), and you should find it cozy enough so that you can get a decent night’s sleep. If you can’t sleep well, then over time, you’ve basically lost everything from your productivity to your sanity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are having trouble finding the funds to buy a couch and a bed, consider either a nicer quality pull-out couch or a day bed. That way, you can have both a bed and a couch in one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very last thing I asked my interviewees was which of these 10 items they would move from a Splurge to Skimp, since they both opted to move the new couch from a Skimp to a Splurge. One of my interviewees chose the new bed to sacrifice, the other chose eating at nice restaurants. I’ve already provided a solution for getting a bed &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; a nice couch, and in terms of eating at nice restaurants, I think the best solution would just be to cook food in the comforts of your own kitchen. I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/rules-of-batch-cooking_n_8401718&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;batch cooking&lt;/a&gt; for the easiest way to have plenty of food in your fridge/freezer without cooking on a daily basis!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that concludes this set of blog posts! I hope that you’ve been able to get some inspiration to help get your own budget started! Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you to Beth Heming and Joel Sax for letting me interview them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* This category has been renamed from &quot;Netflix&quot; to &quot;Video Streaming Services&quot; to account for more than just Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/skimp-and-splurge/2019-12-28-from-others-perspectives/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/skimp-and-splurge/2019-12-28-from-others-perspectives/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DNS, Domains, and Personal Websites</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s many companies that provide the ability for individuals to have their own websites. They include &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; (where this site is hosted), &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/product/pages/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitLab Pages&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blogger.com/about/?r=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wix.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wix&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/a/users/answer/9314941?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Sites&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weebly.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Weebly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hostgator.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HostGator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.godaddy.com/websites/website-builder&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theknot.com/gs/wedding-websites&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Knot&lt;/a&gt;. That’s only naming a few. Every single site has their own pros and cons. Some provide more themes. Some provide more flexibility but require the user to know how to code. Some are completely free but usually sacrifice flexibility and theme options. Some start as free but then have payment plans to get more features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals may choose different hosting options for different websites, depending on their needs for the site. As an example, I have two maintained websites on my domain. This is my first one. I host on GitHub Pages because I feel comfortable enough to code and maintain my own site, and I like the flexibility it provides. But I also host a site on Google Sites. I host there because it doesn’t need a fancy theme, and setup needed to be extra fast (I managed to easily set up that site within four hours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People may choose to have a website for multiple reasons, including: personal blogs, advertisement of themselves and their career, a business they’re starting, etc. The good news is that with the internet, people can basically make a website for whatever they want (my partner once had one that just had a bunch of pictures of legos he made). The bad news is that unless you specifically set your website to be private (and that feature is only available from some hosting companies), anybody browsing the web can find your website. Pros and cons, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, one thing is for certain. Basically, no matter how where you decide to host your website, there’s going to be an option to provide your own domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of these sites will provide you with half-customized domain. This could look like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;myblog.wordpress.com&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firstnamelastname.weebly.com&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;github-user.github.io&lt;/code&gt;. For the company, this is really easy to do. The user can choose whatever the front portion of that should be (called a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subdomain&lt;/code&gt;). And then the back portion (the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;domain&lt;/code&gt; itself—ex: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wordpress.com&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;weebly.com&lt;/code&gt;) functions both as an advertisement for their service, and it is easy to manage and make SSL certificates for (it’s what’s called a wildcard domain: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*.wordpress.com&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, for many individuals, that’s not quite enough customization for their website (including myself). For whatever reason we each choose, we don’t want to advertise where our website was hosted just by the URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;domains&quot;&gt;Domains&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some small amount of money annually (usually around $10–$15 per year), an individual can purchase a custom domain name. Each domain name is unique. So since &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;facebook.com&lt;/code&gt; is already purchased, nobody else can get this domain. Hopefully nobody’s name is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Faceb Ook&lt;/code&gt;. My domain for my website is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emmasax4.info&lt;/code&gt;, so nobody else can buy that, but they could buy &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emmasax4.com&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emmasax.info&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A URL (or Uniform Resource Locator) has multiple parts to it. The first part is the protocol identifier. This is typically &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https&lt;/code&gt; (the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;s&lt;/code&gt; means secure connection with an SSL certificate). Other examples of protocols may be &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ftp&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;telnet&lt;/code&gt;. The last two portions (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;) is the domain. This the unique name that indicates where the website is being served from. The ending part (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.edu&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.net&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gov&lt;/code&gt;, etc) indicates the top-level domain designator. Here are some common top-level domains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive-sm&quot;&gt;
  &lt;table class=&quot;table table-hover table-bordered&quot;&gt;
    &lt;thead class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Top-Level Domain&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Commercial Entity&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Most common for companies that wish to advertise and sell a product.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;This includes nonprofit organizations.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.edu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Educational Institution&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;This could include universities, colleges, and high schools.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.net&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Network Provider&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Originally designated for companies involved with internet organizations.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.gov&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Government&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Originally only for the federal government, but now it includes any level of government.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the top-level domain is also a country code, such as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.us&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.ca&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.de&lt;/code&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next part of the domain (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;example&lt;/code&gt;) is the unique identifier. This is what individuals can typically customize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything before that (including a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;www&lt;/code&gt;) is a subdomain. The history of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;www&lt;/code&gt; is sort of old-fashioned. It was first made with the idea that every single domain would start with this, as it stands for World Wide Web. But now, that’s outdated, and it’s more common for websites to just omit that portion of the URL entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An individual can also use subdomains to have &quot;multiple websites&quot; that are all part of the same website (ex: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;blog.example.com&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals can also use their domain as a part of their email (for the ultimate professional look). This would look like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jsmith@example.com&lt;/code&gt;, and the domain would be &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dns&quot;&gt;DNS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, now that we’ve done an overview of domains, we can talk about DNS. DNS stands for Domain Name System, and is what the internet uses to map each domain to the IP address of the server that’s hosting the website. But IP addresses change regularly, they’re ugly to look at, and hard to remember. Therefore, we often map domains to other domains, which then will map to several other places to get to a final destination IP address. But all you—as the reader—needs to know is that when you purchase a domain, whatever service you purchase that from is also going to give you a DNS. And it’s in &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; DNS where you can define where you want your domain name(s) to map to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s several different types of configurations. The basic thing to know is that there are &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A Records&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ALIAS Records&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CNAME Records&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A Records&lt;/code&gt; map a domain to an IP address (when the IP address is known and stable). A &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CNAME Record&lt;/code&gt; maps a domain to another domain (leading to that daisy chain I was briefly describing in the paragraph above). &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ALIAS Records&lt;/code&gt; are a lot like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CNAME Record&lt;/code&gt;s, but they can coexist with other records on that name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;domains--your-website&quot;&gt;Domains + Your Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s walk through some examples of these DNS records may look like if you set up your website on a few different host providers. Note that TTL stands for Time to Live, and it specifies how long a resolver is supposed to cache the DNS query before looking for any new DNS queries. I purchased and manage my DNS on &lt;a href=&quot;https://namecheap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; (that’s not a secret, so I don’t feel bad disclosing that at all).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS records when setting up your website with your main domain on GitHub Pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Type               Host                 Value                     TTL
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
ALIAS Record            @            github-user.github.io.        Automatic
CNAME Record           www               mydomain.com.             Automatic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS records when setting up your website your your main domain on Google Sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Type               Host                 Value                     TTL
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
ALIAS Record             @            ghs.googlehosted.com.        Automatic
CNAME Record            www               mydomain.com.            Automatic
TXT Record               @          google-site-verification=...   Automatic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* The Google Site Verification is how Google verifies that you are the owner of the domain you wish to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS records when setting up your website with your main domain on Wordpress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Type               Host                 Value                     TTL
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
ALIAS Record            @             NS1.WORDPRESS.COM.           Automatic
ALIAS Record            @             NS2.WORDPRESS.COM.           Automatic
ALIAS Record            @             NS3.WORDPRESS.COM.           Automatic
CNAME Record           www               mydomain.com.             Automatic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NS1.WORDPRESS.COM&lt;/code&gt; are WordPress’s name server resolvers. These servers are in charge of finding the IP addresses belonging to &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; WordPress site out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS records when setting up your website with a subdomain on GitHub Pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Type               Host                 Value                     TTL
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
CNAME Record         subdomain       github-user.github.io.        Automatic
CNAME Record       www.subdomain     subdomain.mydomain.com.       Automatic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS records when setting up your website with a subdomain on Google Sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Type               Host                 Value                     TTL
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
CNAME Record         subdomain        ghs.googlehosted.com.        Automatic
CNAME Record       www.subdomain     subdomain.mydomain.com.       Automatic
TXT Record           subdomain     google-site-verification=...    Automatic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS records when setting up your website with a subdomain on Wordpress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Type               Host                 Value                     TTL
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
CNAME Record         subdomain     wordpress-site.wordpress.com.   Automatic
CNAME Record       www.subdomain     subdomain.mydomain.com.       Automatic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t worked with adding domains to any other website host providers, so I can’t speak to any other providers’ information. But, when a person goes to add a domain to their website, there’s usually plenty of (decently 🤞🏼) helpful documentation to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you go! Hopefully this has helped you either learn more about DNS and domains, or will help you in choosing your personal domain and setting it up on your new website! Best of luck. I can attest that having your own website can be fun! It gives you a fun hobby and project, and it’s definitely something that you can be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://howdns.works/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hownds.works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dyn.com/blog/dyn-tech-everything-you-ever-wanted-to-know-about-ttls/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dyn.com: everything you ever wanted to know about ttls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.dnsimple.com/articles/differences-between-a-cname-alias-url/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;suppor.dnsimple.com: differences between a cname alias url&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Why-do-some-websites-have-www-at-the-start-but-others-have-http&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;quora.com: why do some websites have www at the start but others have http&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oit.edu/libraries/help/internet-guides/understanding-parts-of-internet-address&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.oit.edu: understanding parts of internet address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webopedia.com/TERM/U/URL.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.webopedia: url.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/howto/18799/add-your-own-domain-to-your-wordpress.com-blog/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.howtogeek.com: add your own domain to your wordpress.com blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-do-you-call-the-section-at-the-end-of-an-email-that-includes-peoples-job-contact-info-etc-How-can-I-design-one-for-myself&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;quora.com: what do you call the section at the end of an email that includes peoples job contact info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://namecheap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;namecheap.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-20-dns-domains-and-personal-websites/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-20-dns-domains-and-personal-websites/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using &lt;header-code&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/header-code&gt;</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I started the endeavor of adding Bootstrap to this website. You can read more about how this repository uses Bootstrap, and how to add Bootstrap to a static content site &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/posts/2019-12-17-adding-bootstrap-to-your-static-content-site/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, soon after I started getting an upgrade in my CSS game, I realized that my pagination bar on my blog site was sorely outdated 😢. At one point, I had the nerve to call this pagination bar beautiful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/184539266@N08/48741504061/in/album-72157710863695862/&quot; title=&quot;lovely_pagination_bar&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;my-image&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/48741504061_7ebbd630fa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; alt=&quot;Lovely pagination bar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since completely revamping the whole looks of the site, this pagination bar was no longer acceptable. It was old fashioned, wouldn’t remember the page you were on if you navigated forward and back in your browser, and didn’t have pretty buttons. It was time for me to look into alternate pagination options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I build and serve this site with GitHub Pages. Their built-in pagination suggestion is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-paginate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But, it very clearly states that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate&lt;/code&gt; is no longer supported. The recommended newer version of Jekyll pagination is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had considered &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt; before, and I briefly mentioned it in &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/posts/2019-09-12-adding-pagination-without-jekyll/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I didn’t want to make the necessary changes to my directory structure, and I’d have to be willing to either add a trailing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; to the end of my URLs, or I’d have to be okay with some of my pages having that trailing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;, and some not to, which I wasn’t okay with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a technical standpoint, it doesn’t really matter to the browser whether you write a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; on the end of your URL or not; they resolve to the same host. There’s more detailed reasons why or why to have a trailing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; on a URL, but the gist is that the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; delineates a directory, which then would have files in it: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://example.com/directory/&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://example.com/directory/file.html&lt;/code&gt; 🤷🏻‍♀️.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, my reading said that although having URLs without &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; is the newer, more popular thing, traditionalists would actually pretty much only have &lt;em&gt;either&lt;/em&gt; the trailing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; the extension (the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt; in the above example) in the URL. So if I’m to follow these guidelines, then I probably should add the trailing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; to the end of all of my URLs except the home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could continue doing research, trying to decide what other pagination options to explore. But I figured that if I wanted to get anything easy done reasonably soon, I’d have to just be okay with compromising on the trailing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after admitting that I’d need to accept the trailing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;, I proceeded to set up &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt; on my repository. How hard could it be? 😆&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2#installation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;installation instructions&lt;/a&gt;. But, as you’ll understand later, I got only got through the second line in that section; I never finished reading that doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I jumped right into the work, copy-pasting the basics of the needed configuration into my config file, before realizing that although there’s lots of documentation in this repo, they never quite clarify that your main &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/code&gt; page needs to be in a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;./blog/index.html&lt;/code&gt; file. Furthermore, they never actually say that your blog posts need to be in a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts/&lt;/code&gt; directory. Luckily, I poked around the examples enough to figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/alialo/2255511&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to get the basic code of a simple pagination bar going right away. In fact, getting the main &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/code&gt; page paginating wasn’t too hard at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I also wanted to make sure that I could paginate my sub-pages—basically filtering my posts based on tag names and set names. On my site, an example of a tag name is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tech&lt;/code&gt; and an example of a set name is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Welcome to Kenya&lt;/code&gt;. The distinction between the two is that a blog post can have multiple tag names, and they should be one word long. But a blog post can only be a part of one set, and the name can be multiple words with capitalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filtering posts proved to be a little bit more complicated than just paginating &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the posts. The documentation for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt; describes filtering based on what they call &quot;tags&quot; and &quot;categories&quot;. So I started with a single tag, because I wasn’t quite sure yet how to deal with the sets. After I added the first bit of code to the tag’s filter, I realized that the documentation never properly mentioned in what &lt;em&gt;directory&lt;/em&gt; I should put my filter’s file. I tried at least four different places I should put it. It wasn’t until my last idea when I realized that it had to be placed in the same &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;blog/&lt;/code&gt; directory as the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;. But, as soon as I moved my tag file into the directory, so it looked like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;blog/tag.html&lt;/code&gt;, then it worked miraculously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was then easy to move all of the tags to have the same pattern. Moving to the &quot;set&quot;, I had more issues, mainly with 1) figuring out the best way to paginate the filtered pages, and 2) &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt; couldn’t be formatted to work with filtering a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;set&lt;/code&gt; (only &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;locales&lt;/code&gt;, which is languages). So, I had to write my code as if my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;set&lt;/code&gt; was a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;category&lt;/code&gt; instead. This meant changing several variable names, and in general renaming files and calls to have the word &quot;category&quot; instead of &quot;set&quot;. In fact, by the end of the night, I had changed almost every reference to a &quot;set&quot; in the whole codebase 😝.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, by the time I was done for the day, I had pretty much decided to just do-away with the whole notion of a &quot;set&quot; and turn it into a &quot;category&quot; instead. Actually I like the word &quot;collection&quot; more than a &quot;category&quot;, so in the codebase it’s a &quot;category&quot;, in my head it’s a &quot;collection&quot;, and to an end user of this site, they all look like &quot;tags&quot;. So then, I did a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; find/replace of the word &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;set&lt;/code&gt; and replaced it with the word &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;category&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all of this work, now every single tag and category filters blog posts properly. The last secret to getting pagination working on those pages is that I needed to save the URL of the filtered page: aka &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/blog/welcome-to-kenya&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/blog/tech&lt;/code&gt;. And this way, we could append the page count number to the end of that: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/blog/welcome-to-kenya/4/&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/blog/tech/2/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all of that work, I now have a pagination bar that makes me proud of this website. Just add in a few more pretty icons, and I’m satisfied 😁.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/184539266@N08/49241327792/in/album-72157710863695862/&quot; title=&quot;Bootstrap Pagination&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;my-image&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/49241327792_44bf877bcb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; alt=&quot;Bootstrap Pagination&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haha! You thought the story was over, didn’t you? Well… as soon as I merged in my pull request to add the new pagination, I realized something. That paragraph of the installation instructions that I &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; finish? Well, the ending part of it warned that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-pagination-v2&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; supported by GitHub Pages. This means that when somebody runs the code locally on their computer, they can use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-pagination-v2&lt;/code&gt; to their hearts’ content, and the site will load properly. But GitHub’s servers (which normally build the site for me), will not properly execute &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-pagination-v2&lt;/code&gt;, and there’s no way to compile the pagination code properly without that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had just &lt;em&gt;finished&lt;/em&gt; that section, I could’ve saved me a whole 30 minutes where the site wasn’t broken, and potentially even saved myself a little headache. But at this point, I’ve come too far to turn back around and go back to my old-fashioned pagination. So, Google came to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out (surprise surprise) I’m not the first person to run into this issue. There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2/issues/9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;whole discussion&lt;/a&gt; that’s going on about this topic, and trying to integrate &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt; with GitHub Pages eventually, but it hasn’t made any progress lately. But, I did get some ideas from the discussion. Here are my options of how to proceed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After I finish making any changes to my site, I can commit my new source code to GitHub, bundle the project on my own computer, and then upload the bundled site to a &lt;em&gt;separate&lt;/em&gt; branch in GitHub and have GitHub Pages deploy only &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; branch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can switch to use the GitHub Pages supported &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate&lt;/code&gt; and let GitHub Pages properly paginate my blog posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with the second approach. But after some more research, I learned that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t allow for the filtering of tags and collections, which my site was heavily relying on. Therefore, to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate&lt;/code&gt; would involve completely redoing my site, and several more hours’ work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not a fan of needing my site to have to be built on a person’s computer to work properly. It’s never a good idea to have a website’s deployment rely on a person’s physical computer (which could break, have compilation issues, or generally just not be available). But I figured that other people had run into this issue with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/code&gt; and GitHub Pages, and I’m sure somebody wrote a blog post about it (similarly to like I’m doing now). So I looked up different ways to combat this issue. The blog post I found was &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mcred/supercharge-github-pages-with-jekyll-and-travis-ci-699bc0bde075&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. I owe my entire pagination to &lt;em&gt;that blog post&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically what Derek Smart (I wonder if that’s his real name 🧐) suggests is to go with the first approach, but don’t bundle the project on &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; machine… use a continuous deployment tool. And here comes Travis CI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Travis CI’s documentation,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Continuous Integration is the practice of merging in small code changes frequently - rather than merging in a large change at the end of a development cycle. The goal is to build healthier software by developing and testing in smaller increments. This is where Travis CI comes in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a continuous integration platform, Travis CI supports your development process by automatically building and testing code changes, providing immediate feedback on the success of the change. Travis CI can also automate other parts of your development process by managing deployments and notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ending part of that statement is important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Travis CI can… [manage] deployments and notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we could (in theory) make a change to the source code in GitHub, and then have Travis CI build my website and &quot;deploy&quot; it to GitHub Pages. And, it turns out my site was already using Travis CI to test the Jekyll build process on every commit to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch. So, I only had to add a few lines to have Travis CI &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; deploy my changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;script:
  - JEKYLL_ENV=production bundle exec jekyll build --destination site

deploy:
  provider: pages
  local-dir: ./site
  target-branch: master
  email: deploy@travis-ci.org
  name: Deployment Bot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;script&lt;/code&gt; section asks Travis CI to build the site to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; destination directory. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy&lt;/code&gt; section tells Travis CI to run a deploy to the GitHub Pages provider with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;./site&lt;/code&gt; directory, on the target branch &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, and which GitHub user to use (in this case, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Deployment Bot&lt;/code&gt; with the email &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deploy@travis-ci.org&lt;/code&gt;). There are a few other little pieces to get it working properly, but you can check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emma-sax4/emma-sax4.github.io/blob/release/.travis.yml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt; if you want to see more. I did need to make a new branch in GitHub—the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; branch. The idea here is that the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; branch is used for me to store my source code for this site, and the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch is for GitHub Pages to deploy. Only the fully compiled and bundled site lives on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a little complicated, but, one deploy from Travis CI later, and the site was up and running again. &lt;em&gt;AND&lt;/em&gt; I had the pagination option of my choosing that had all of the functionality I could ever want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;my-image giphy-embed&quot; src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/4xpB3eE00FfBm&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/mrw-week-job-4xpB3eE00FfBm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2/blob/master/README-GENERATOR.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;github.com: jekyll-paginate-v2, README-GENERATOR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;github.com: jekyll-paginate-v2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/5948659/when-should-i-use-a-trailing-slash-in-my-url&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stackoverflow.com: when should I use a trailing slash in my URL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://searchfacts.com/url-trailing-slash/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;searchfacts.com: url trailing slash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/alialo/2255511&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gist.github.com: alialo/2255511&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mcred/supercharge-github-pages-with-jekyll-and-travis-ci-699bc0bde075&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;medium.com: supercharge github pages with jekyll and travis ci&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.travis-ci.com/user/for-beginners/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;docs.travis-ci.com: for beginners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-18-using-jekyll-paginate-v2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-18-using-jekyll-paginate-v2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adding Bootstrap to Your Static Content Site</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Between when I originally turned this website into a Jekyll site and a couple of weeks ago, a decent amount of CSS in the site had been slowly changing. First of all, the navigation bar had gone from a whole quarter of the screen to just a small top bar. The navigation words had moved to the right of the screen. But most importantly, I was attempting to make the site responsive to different screen widths (particularly mobile vs. computer). And there was a point when I realized that there were certain limitations my CSS/HTML knowledge had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it is arguably beneficial for a coder like me (that’s young in my career) to hand-craft all of my site’s CSS, the truth is that the site won’t come out as nicely as if I use a 3rd party tool. And, one could even claim that getting experience in implementing a 3rd party tool, and figuring out the best ways to use it, is even better experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s walk through the process of adding Bootstrap to a Jekyll site, since this is what I did &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;install-bootstrap-into-your-site&quot;&gt;Install Bootstrap into your site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I selected to use the most recent version of Bootstrap (4.4), and wanted to install it via a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and CDN. If you put this line right before where your site links your own stylesheets, then it’ll automatically import this and combine the two CSS’s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link
  rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot;
  href=&quot;https://stackpath.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/4.4.1/css/bootstrap.min.css&quot;
  integrity=&quot;sha384-Vkoo8x4CGsO3+Hhxv8T/Q5PaXtkKtu6ug5TOeNV6gBiFeWPGFN9MuhOf23Q9Ifjh&quot;
  crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot;
&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your site will take all of Bootstrap’s CSS, and then consider whatever you’ve coded as overrides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;load-your-site-locally-and-see-what-breaks-️&quot;&gt;Load your site locally and see what breaks 🤷🏻‍♀️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first loaded my site, a surprising amount of the site successfully showed up. In fact, I’d even say that it pretty much looked exactly like what it was before, because my local CSS was overriding all of Bootstrap’s CSS. The only big thing that changed was my font styles. At the end of the day, I chose to keep Bootstrap’s styles anyway because I started to get used to the new font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your site does start to break, then that’s an indicator that there’s probably some of your custom CSS that you should get rid of. If you’re going to use Bootstrap, you might as well &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; Bootstrap, which includes using most of Bootstrap’s functionality and features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-through-your-css-bit-by-bit-and-delete-those-bits&quot;&gt;Go through your CSS bit by bit and delete those bits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this part, I started with the biggest single element I could find: my navbar. I started by taking a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.0/components/navbar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bootstrap’s built-in navbar&lt;/a&gt;, and worked my way through my particular HTML file implementing a basic version of Bootstrap’s navbar. This involved changing the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; names and moving around the lines of Jekyll code that write the menu on the top. I didn’t care if it was responsive or not; I could get to that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I implemented the basics of the navbar, it worked pretty miraculously. It also turned out to basically be responsive right away, all I had to do was modify a few more &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; names. Then, it was time to make the navbar look like mine (with similar colors, sizing, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Inspect element&lt;/code&gt; on Bootstrap’s website to see what I should name the CSS class in my own repo: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nav.navbar&lt;/code&gt;. Then, I simply copied over my color scheme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nav.navbar {
  background-color: rgb(27, 14, 172);
  background: linear-gradient(to right, rgb(27, 14, 172), rgb(107, 208, 245));
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, right away I could delete all of the old navbar CSS code! This included a solid chunk of lines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I wanted to make it so the menu button (also known as a hamburger 🍔 icon) would turn into an ❌ button when the navbar expanded. This took more time, and to be honest, if not for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brianMitchL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@brianMitchL&lt;/a&gt;’s help, I may still be struggling. In order to save you from struggling, I’ll give you some code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;nav.navbar {
  &amp;gt; .navbar-toggler {
    // The toggle button
  }

  .navbar-toggler[aria-expanded=&quot;false&quot;] &amp;gt; .x {
    // ❌ icon
    display: none;
  }

  .navbar-toggler[aria-expanded=&quot;true&quot;] &amp;gt; .menu {
    // 🍔 icon
    display: none;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with only 20 minutes of work, I have a fully-functioning navbar that fits Accessibility standards, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the navbar, I tackled &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.0/components/buttons/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Boostrap’s buttons&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.0/layout/overview/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;general page layouts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.0/layout/grid/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;columns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do the buttons, you can go through the same process as with the navbar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look up the basic Bootstrap button’s HTML&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your button(s) have the same &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; names&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the button looks like Bootstrap’s then make small tweaks to Bootstrap’s CSS class(es) to make it format like how you want it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete your button CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same process with the columns. To do the page layouts and responsive breakpoints, the only piece of knowledge that I didn’t know (until Brian came along), was that Bootstrap’s automatically going to expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;main class=&quot;container&quot;&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;/main&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I was running that second line without the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;class=&quot;container&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. But, once we added that, suddenly the entire site’s body was fully responsive! Now, everything word-wrapped appropriately from a huge screen, right down to 320px wide (the size of an iPhone 5/SE). It’s brilliant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple days, I eventually completely switched to using &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.0/content/tables/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bootstrap’s tables&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.0/components/pagination/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bootstrap’s pagination&lt;/a&gt; (but I’ll get to that in another blog post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day (or a few days), my repo ended up going from over 650 lines of CSS code to 185 lines. That means I cut out at least 72% of my existing CSS code. &lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt; I have a better-looking, more responsive, more modern, and accessible website? It’s a win-win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for getting to the bottom of that rather technical blog post. I hope it’s enough compelling evidence to remember that using a 3rd party tool to make your website’s CSS better is worth it. If I (a back-end coder with very little CSS experience) can make it happen, then so can you 😉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about how my site uses Bootstrap, please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emma-sax4/emma-sax4.github.io/blob/release/.notes/bootstrap_in_this_site.md&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this document&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more about Bootstrap, please read their documentation &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.4/getting-started/introduction/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-17-adding-bootstrap-to-your-static-content-site/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-17-adding-bootstrap-to-your-static-content-site/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thanksgivings Aren't About Food 🍽</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, I know what you all may be thinking. &quot;Of course Thanksgiving is about the food!&quot; And I understand why you believe that. I get that many people feel this way. For many Americans, connecting with friends and family over food is totally normal and is a healthy way to bond with loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to get together with old high school friends, you all go out for brunch. When you go on a first date, you go out to dinner. When you visit with your family, including your crazy Uncle Jim, you get together for dinner so you can get some 🥃 inside him so his political jokes won’t be as rude. When you go out for a business meeting, you go for lunch or for coffee. Americans, and possibly humans in general, love to bond over food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it comes to Thanksgiving, it’s all about the food. The turkey 🦃, gravy, stuffing, etc. One household bites the bullet and decides to cook a lavish meal for their whole family. They stay up late on Wednesday cooking, and work tirelessly throughout Thursday morning and afternoon to prep even more food. And then, at the end of the meal, there’s tons of leftovers. Leftovers for days! So many leftovers that you can hardly fit them all into the fridge. And inevitably, the house won’t be able to finish all of the leftovers by the time they go bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying that any of these habits are wrong. In fact, for many people and many households, it’s a great tradition. But there are some people and some families that don’t make Thanksgiving about the food. It’s about spending time with family, catching up with one another, and being grateful for all of the things in their lives 🙇🏻‍♀️. They may eat a meal, but that’s only because if you’re together all afternoon, wouldn’t you get hungry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the truth is, that for many people with eating disorders, or people that are on strict eating programs, Thanksgiving is not a friendly meal for them. Being part of a holiday that is so centered on eating tons of food isn’t a healthy environment for some of these people to be in. Yes, everybody’s experiences with it are going to be different. I can only speak to mine. Personally, I’ve been trying to eat healthier foods. And so, being around all of the pie 🥧, rolls 🥖, and chocolates 🍫 wasn’t easy. This was exacerbated by the fact that my partner and I spent one Thanksgiving meal at my parents’ house, and one at his mom’s house. So we had &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; dinners!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my family was so understanding of the stress of this holiday. So my family did something new. We had an extremely healthy Thanksgiving! We’re all vegetarian, so we skipped the turkey, gravy, and mashed potatoes. We had mashed cauliflower and sweet potatoes 🥔 as a substitute. We didn’t have any pie or ice cream, and instead had fresh fruit 🍓🍇 for dessert. Personally, I didn’t eat any sugar at Thanksgiving, which is definitely a first for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this whole post boils down to is that for many Americans, their favorite part of Thanksgiving is the feast. There’s nothing wrong with that whatsoever. But for me, and for a solid chunk of Americans, it’s good to remember that the food wasn’t the original purpose of Thanksigiving (ignoring the whole colonization/Native American topic right now). The original purpose was to &quot;give thanks for one’s blessings, along with… [celebrating] …a harvest.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that, have a happy holiday season, filled with love, joy, and gratefulness for one’s family and friends 🥂.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thanksgiving_(United_States)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wikipedia.org: Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-01-thanksgivings-arent-about-food/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-12-01-thanksgivings-arent-about-food/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Kenya</title>
        
          <subtitle>Special: Can the Northern White Rhinoceros come back?</subtitle>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over two months ago I wrote my second installment of the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/welcome-to-kenya/&quot;&gt;Welcome to Kenya&lt;/a&gt; blog collection. In it, I told the shortened version of the story of the northern white rhinos. Please read about it &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/posts/welcome-to-kenya/2019-09-16-the-game-drives/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for context before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, social media blew up over a posted picture of Jimmy John Liautaud, the founder and owner of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jimmyjohns.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jimmy Johns&lt;/a&gt;, posing in front of a dead African elephant, which he had killed as part of a hunting game drive. This upset me very much. Not only does this type of hunting make me cringe, but I’m also immediately concerned because I know that some species of African elephants are endangered. After doing more research, I found that Liautaud has also hunted giraffes, leopards, zebras, lions, and rhinoceroses. This last animal made me even more disgusted. There’s an actual picture on Twitter of Liautaud killing the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;last female northern white rhino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mangetti_National_Park&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mangetti Nation Park&lt;/a&gt; in Namibia. Liautaud has literally contributed to the endangerment of northern white rhinos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to do two things. First, I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23boycottjimmyjohns&amp;amp;src=typeahead_click&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#boycottjimmyjohns&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve never boycotted a restaurant before, but here goes nothing. I know that realistically, my boycott won’t make much of a difference to a restaurant chain that just keeps growing in popularity, but intentionally not supporting and/or giving money to this man makes me feel a little bit better. Secondly, I decided to check back up on those rhino eggs that were fertilized in August of this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, in light of all of these recent events, I decided to write a special blog post beyond the original five I intended to write. And the news is in: the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olpejetaconservancy.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ol Pejeta Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://safaripark.cz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dvür Králové Zoo&lt;/a&gt; have created the first ever Northern White Rhino in-vitro embryos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For decades the story of the northern white rhinoceros has been a tale of decline. The number of individuals shrank down to only two in 2018, rendering complete extinction as only a matter of time. An international consortium of scientists and conservationists has now achieved a milestone in assisted reproduction that may be a pivotal turning point in the fate of these magnificent animals. Using eggs collected from the two remaining females and frozen sperm from deceased males, they successfully created two northern white rhino embryos. The embryos are now stored in liquid nitrogen to be transferred into a surrogate mother in the near future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This groundbreaking news provides the opportunity to save the northern white rhinos, one animal at a time. Now, I don’t want to make things seem happier than they are. This is a huge breakthrough, but there’s still a lot at risk. Having four northern white rhinos doesn’t mean the species can grow in strength. There are still many risks (as with any birth), and the potential to be able to make more rhino babies after these ones is still limited. It will take decades of research, work, and failed attempts at fertilization in order to bring back a small northern white population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All we can hope is that the world sees these beautiful creatures and understands that losing them would be a devastating loss for our ecosystem and our world. I hope Kenya can work to protect these rhinos from poachers like Jimmy John Liautaud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olpejetaconservancy.org/saving-the-northern-whites/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;olpejetaconservancy.org: saving the northern whites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.olpejetaconservancy.org/first-ever-in-vitro-embryos/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;olpejetaconservancy.org: first ever in-vitro embryos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aol.com/article/finance/2019/08/23/jimmy-johns-boycott-ceo-jimmy-john-liautaud-elephant-hunting-photo-goes-viral/23800248/?fbclid=IwAR3ZGSFAQ3btXRtEefAPq9oMNOFlterroWAz54rNyRuTLAwqWjJXkXXU9dM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;aol.com: jimmy johns boycott ceo jimmy john liautaud elephant hunting photo goes viral&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SikhProf/status/1164894341921480704&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;twitter.com: @SikhProf post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/welcome-to-kenya/2019-11-20-can-the-northern-white-rhinocerous-come-back/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/welcome-to-kenya/2019-11-20-can-the-northern-white-rhinocerous-come-back/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skimp and Splurge</title>
        
          <subtitle>Part 2: Three Years Later</subtitle>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I dug out the original post &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/posts/skimp-and-splurge/2019-10-19-the-art-of-saving-money&quot;&gt;Skimp and Splurge: The Art of Saving Money&lt;/a&gt; from my Google Drive, I was immediately humored by my original intent to create a blog. As you can probably tell, that never actually came to fruition… Until I decided to adventure with GitHub Pages. Although, most of that is another story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What actually inspired me to publish that original &quot;post&quot; from 2016 was that a lot of the opinions I had on it have changed. When I wrote that originally, I wasn’t even graduated from college yet. I was still living in a dorm room (suite, technically), and I still had a small meal plan at my college’s Dining Hall. I had a decent amount of money for a senior in college (since I worked part-time at SportsEngine during the last couple years of school), but that didn’t necessarily prepare me for what living in the &quot;real world&quot; would be like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I learned quickly was that money doesn’t grow on trees. What takes a person two weeks to earn goes pretty quickly when your rent is $1,300/month, your car payment is $400/month, and you still want to go out to eat at restaurants. And so, as I moved out of my parents home in the summer of 2017, my priorities began to shift away from what I thought they’d look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in honor of it being almost exactly three years after that original post, let’s re-evaluate those 10 skimps and splurges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKIMP: daily coffee&lt;/strong&gt;. In fact, I don’t drink any coffee at all. Call me lucky that I don’t need the pick-me-up of energy in the morning, but because of it, I can easily save $150 a month from frequent trips to Starbucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don’t drink coffee. When I was in high school, everyone would tell me: &quot;You may not need the caffeine yet, but just wait until college.&quot; When I got to college, everyone said: &quot;You’re a young freshman. Just wait until you’re a senior.&quot; When I became a senior, people said: &quot;It’s amazing you don’t need coffee right now, but just wait until after you graduate and start working full-time.&quot; And yet, here I am, 2.5 years after graduation, working full-time, and I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; don’t drink coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe I’ve had maybe three cups of coffee in my entire life, and each one of those had to be loaded up with sugars and creams to hide the bitter taste. In fact, one time my mom came over to my apartment and I offered her a cup of coffee. She said &quot;that would be great&quot;, and then I offered to take my car to Starbucks—I don’t own a coffee maker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPLURGE: apartment rent&lt;/strong&gt;. Even though apartments provide a low-contract living situation, I like knowing that the place I’m living in is decently nice, in a good neighborhood, and I would feel comfortable living there for years to come if I wanted to. And it’s not like I was super picky. In fact, my requirement for living there included 6 things:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Central heat&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Air conditioning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dishwasher&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Underground parking available&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Free laundry (does not necessarily mean in-unit washer/dryer)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fitness room in building&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I moved out of my parents home, I’ve lived in three apartments. And it’s been only 2.5 years! There are some things in this category that haven’t changed. I still like to live in a decently nice place. I will always try my darnedest not to live in a place where there’s thefts, break-ins, and gunshots at night. But, it’s okay if my apartment doesn’t have a state-of-the-art gym facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s my revised list of requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Central heat (we do live in Minnesota, so hopefully this is common)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air conditioning (less common than heat, but decently easy to find)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dishwasher (considering I use mine at least five times a week, I’d say this is a necessity for me)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Underground parking available (I would also settle for an individual single-stall garage, because then I can use that for storage, but I do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; like brushing snow and ice off in the morning)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laundry (this doesn’t need to be free, and it doesn’t need to be in-unit, but I do think I’d put my foot down on the place if the machines used quarters)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fitness room in building (even though I don’t go to the gym as often as I’d like to admit, it’s still nice having this option in the building)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mail and package receiving (normal mail is common, package rooms are a newer amentity that I could see older complexes not having)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No smoking in the building or on balconies (this is actually a huge one for me as a non-smoker…. I hate the smell of cigarettes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comcast as an optional internet provider (since I work for NBCUniversal and Comcast, I get free internet and cable; there’s no way I would willingly pay another internet provider when I could just get free internet through my work)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonus: an indoor swimming pool and hot tub (I love to swim, in fact, it’s probably my most preferred sport, so having these as bonus amentities make living anywhere way more enjoyable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… I guess my requirements list has gotten even longer. But one huge thing I have learned is that you may find an apartment that’s great, and then learn that it’s not as great as you thought. It’s okay to move when your lease is over. In fact, financially that may be the best option, if your rent is increasing by a significant amount for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKIMP: tons of new clothes&lt;/strong&gt;. Call it luck that at my job, jeans and t-shirts are totally appropriate, but I never am willing to spend more than about $30 on a shirt or a pair of pants if I don’t have to. Stay away from the designer stores and expensive retail stores. I only buy expensive clothes when I know I’ll be wearing them to a very important occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has pretty much stayed the same. But unfortunately, what ends up happening is that I end up buying such cheap clothing that it only lasts a year. I know that if I paid a bit more on a more expensive version, it would actually be better quality. But in my defense, I actually have raised my maximum price range of a piece of clothing to more like $50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPLURGE: eating at nice restaurants&lt;/strong&gt;. I don’t mean super pricey restaurants, just ones that aren’t fast-food chains. I would never skip on going out to eat with an old friend at a decently nice restaurant. Worst case scenario, I’m fed with good-tasting food, my wallet is $45 lighter, and I’ve gotten some socializing done with friend(s). Could be worse. And I’ll probably get leftovers out of it, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve begun to switch up my diet in favor of healthy foods that are homecooked. I make simple, easy-to-remember recipes. But I’ve also learned that I can save a lot of money by not going out to eat. Cooking food at home is cheaper and healthier. I will say that eating a bunch of frozen meals will add up, so instead I’ve been opting for pasta, beans, rice, eggs, fresh fruit, and frozen veggies. Cheap and easy to cook!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5&quot;&gt;5.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKIMP: tons of takeout and fast-food&lt;/strong&gt;. Although it doesn’t seem like much, a month’s worth of take out fees and fast-food adds up. I’d much rather cook one meal, and have it and its leftovers last me three days than spend $5-10 every two days on lunches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my answer to #4 has changed, it makes sense that this one would stay very much the same. Unless I’m in a rush, fast food isn’t really worth it. And McDonald’s is way more expensive now than I feel like it was when I was younger. Now, a Big Mac is almost $5!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6&quot;&gt;6.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPLURGE: Netflix&lt;/strong&gt;. Of course everyone will have different opinions about this, but for me, Netflix is a necessity. Almost right up there with internet. For me, Netflix can easily occupy 3 hours worth of time, and it is a good distraction from the rest of your life when you just need a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completely agree on the Netflix debate as I did three years ago. In fact, now I use Netflix, Hulu, Amazon Prime, the occasional Redbox DVD, and my internet provider’s cable subscription to watch TV shows! Granted, I don’t quite pay for all of these myself. I use my parents’ Netflix still (that’s a long story, but I’m still on strike—thank you Mom and Dad!), and my old friend’s Hulu account. If I was paying for them myself, then I’d try to cut down some of these unless I was sharing the bill with a roommate or a significant other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one tool I would totally recommend is the public library. If you’re willing to wait a few months, then you should take advantage of that old library card you had when you were 12, and put some DVD’s and TV shows on hold at the library! You’ll most likely be waiting a while, but (assuming you have a DVD player), it’s a convenient and free (!) way to watch DVDs and TV shows. Then, you just return it to the library when you’re done (make sure to return on time to avoid late fees).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7&quot;&gt;7.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKIMP: expensive phone bills with tons of unused data&lt;/strong&gt;. If you plan on getting Internet and WiFi at your apartment, like most people have, then you can skip on the data a little bit. For me, 5GB is plenty for the occasional watching of videos and browsing the web. But to each their own (some people use over 10GB a month, and I know that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to phone bills, paying some amount of money for a phone bill is a given. But, the truth still stands that if your home and work have WiFi, then you most likely won’t need a lot of data. These days, I use my phone for navigation more and more while driving, and I occasionally stream Apple Music in the car, so I need some data for that. But I probably don’t use more than 4GB a month. Make sure to shop around for the cheapest plan you can get, and always jump at the chance to share your bill with roommates or SOs. Oftentimes, having one account with multiple phones is cheaper than each person paying individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8&quot;&gt;8.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPLURGE: a good car&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, my car was not cheap. I got a brand new Honda CR-V, with only 11 miles on it. The reason I got this car was because I think of it like an investment. If I bought a cheap car with 120,000 miles on it and it needed maintenance and new parts, then I spend the original amount on the car, plus gas, insurance, the maintenance, and parts. And, it could only last me 2-3 more years. But, if I buy a nice car that isn’t old and doesn’t need a lot of work, assuming I take proper care of the car, it could potentially last me 7 more years. And, I love my car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still stand by this belief. It’s important to have a good car that will last. My car hardly needs maintenance (besides routine tire rotations, tire alignments, and oil changes), but not much more, because it’s still so new. My coworker’s car has been in the auto shop for the past week, just getting fixed up to driveable condition because it’s much older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However…. I got my car new…. and that’s definitely not the most financially responsible thing to do. I should’ve gotten a used car that was a few years old. It still would’ve lasted just as long, and it would’ve been cheaper by about $5k. But, I opted for the newest safety features when I got my car, and those were only available in newer CR-V models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one other thing I’d recommend against is fixing your car up when you bump into something. Everybody gets some damage on their car eventually. Whether that’s scratches, running into a pole in the parking lot, bumping your back bumper into a snowbank, etc. In my limited experience, paying the shop to fix it up is rarely worth it. There was one time where I ran into the back of a semi truck, and my passenger-side mirror cracked. Replacing that was worth it because I couldn’t see out of it. That was affecting my ability to drive my vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But another time I ran into a pole in my parking garage at my apartment. And I paid to have parts of the rear moldings replaced. It cost about $450. And, I decided to leave some scratches in the paint because fixing those would be even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; expensive. But later that summer, my car fell victim to a hit-and-run in another parking lot. I did decide to get that fixed up (and my insurance deductible was a terrible $750). The only good news is that I convinced the auto shop to fix up the other scratches that were still remaining from the pole incident. In hindsight, I probably didn’t need to spend $1,200 to fix my car up from those incidents. Neither of the accidents were affecting the drive of my vehicle, so they were all cosmetic. And if I didn’t care about my car so dang much, I would’ve been fine leaving them the way they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry… I’ve switched my auto insurance now, so my deductible is lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9&quot;&gt;9.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SKIMP: buying a couch right when I move out&lt;/strong&gt;. The truth is, when you first move out, there are some things you need. Some pots and pans, and a shower curtain fall under that list. There are also some things you don’t need right away. A couch and a TV are in that list. Couches are expensive. Besides the bed/mattress and the dining table/chairs, it’ll be in the top 5 most expensive things you’ll buy for quite a while (at least in terms of furniture). Therefore, skip the couch. If you’re a college student, you’re probably used to lying on your bed watching cute animal videos anyway, so you’ll do just fine without a couch if you wait a couple months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first moved out, I did buy a couch. But hold on before you go judging me. I used some money given to me by my aunt who had recently past away. If I was buying all of my furniture out of my own pocket, I would’ve skipped out on the couch. But, since my aunt past away earlier in the summer, she had left me and my sister a small amount of money. I decided to use that to furnish my new apartment, which my aunt would never see. I’m sure she’s proud of the fact that my furniture was all the proper color scheme to match the apartment. I’ve moved a couple more times since, but every piece of furniture I bought transferred to the new apartments nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, it turns out that when you don’t have any pets to chew up your cushions, your Ikea furniture can actually last a long time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10&quot;&gt;10.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPLURGE: a good bed&lt;/strong&gt;. The thing with mattresses is, the better quality mattress you buy, the longer it’ll last, the more comfortable it’ll be, and the better you’ll sleep. And hopefully you’ll learn sometime in your adult life that sleeping is never something you should skimp on if you can help it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes, yes to this! I bought my bed and frame on sale for $1k from Macy’s, and it was worth it. I love having a comfortable bed. Granted, now I know that I could’ve done a little more research to find a mattress that would’ve suited my sleeping needs more, but this one will do the trick, at least for the next 8 years or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you go! I hope that taking another look at my opinions on these topics proves useful for you, and gives you a place to start from if you’re looking at creating or re-evaluating your budget. Let me know what your opinions on these topics are! Shoot me an email from the link in the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact-me/&quot;&gt;Contact Me&lt;/a&gt; tab!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/skimp-and-splurge/2019-11-12-three-years-later/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/skimp-and-splurge/2019-11-12-three-years-later/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More Websites, Jekyll, and DNS</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, for the first time in a couple of months, I felt the need to do more with my Jekyll website(s). GitHub Pages provides an opportunity to host as many sites as I wish, as long as their repository code is public and I’m okay with the resulting site being public. I wasn’t really okay with that situation, so instead, I opted to look at GitHub Pro. GitHub Pro offered to host my GitHub Pages site on repositories that were private, which was basically exactly what I wanted. I know that GitLab Pages could provide me with that same setup for free, but my whole world is on GitHub, and I didn’t quite feel the need to switch that up yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to having a private website though, neither GitHub Pages nor GitLab Pages offers that. So, I went to the handy-dandy Google for how to protect a GitHub pages site. I ended up finding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chrisssycollins/protected-github-pages&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@chrisssycollins’ repo &lt;em&gt;protected-github-pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Although the first Google result was actually basically the same thing (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/matteobrusa/Password-protection-for-static-pages&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@matteobrusa’s &lt;em&gt;Password-protection-for-static-pages&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), I found I liked the documentation in @chrisssycollins’ version better than @matteobrusa’s version. #SorryNotSorry. 🤷🏻‍♀️. So, I’ll acknowledge @chrisssycollins’ version in my post and README.md instead 😉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started working on two new GitHub Pages sites I started to play around with the different Jekyll themes. It turns out that my original site (this one) was made so long ago that a decent amount about the themes have changed since then. Now, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pages-themes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@pages-themes&lt;/a&gt; manages most of the GitHub Pages themes (instead of the individual creators of the themes). They also do this thing where you can &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@import {{ site.theme }};&lt;/code&gt; into the CSS files, assuming that the theme is set in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;. What this means is that new users of the themes don’t need to copy-paste all of the CSS files if they just want &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; the CSS settings of the original themes. This means that it’s very possible that getting your GitHub Pages site up and running is fast… like super fast… like within-a-day-fast. In fact, both of my new GitHub Pages sites were running and live within a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this also means is that, since none of the CSS is actually &lt;em&gt;in your repository&lt;/em&gt;, when you want to make changes to the CSS (say edit the size of a button, change the font, etc), you need to go to the CSS source on GitHub, search in the entire repository for the piece that you need, and then copy-paste that entire element back to your repo and make the changes. To find exactly which piece of CSS required to make a change, I had to play a lot with using Chrome’s Inspect option on my local site. Chrome’s Inspect feature allowed me to find the exact value that I’d need to edit so I copy-pasted the proper CSS element into my local repository 😕. I’m sure that changing the themes’ CSS pattern had good intentions, but I actually found it quite annoying. Perhaps the &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; annoying part of this is that when running Jekyll locally, I got a petty warning about the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_includes/&lt;/code&gt; directory not found in the source layout. Since I use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_includes/&lt;/code&gt; directory in every project, this was particularly irritating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead, I went through each GitHub Pages repository I was using and copy-pasted &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the CSS code into my own directory, and then removed the setting of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;. Now there’s a ton of CSS lines in my repos, but I don’t really mind, especially if all of the CSS can now be in one condensed file and repository, instead of calling a bunch of other files/repos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took the weekend to standardize all of the code that sources my sites, so the directory and file layout of them all match. I even made another site that has nice buttons that lists to each of my sites and their respective code. I also made that repo private and put in password protection. There’s links to my other private site there, so I don’t want people to figure out a way into the originally private site. So putting an extra password in for the new list of sites (that the world can’t get to) is beneficial for me. (I should clarify that hackers could probably get in… I didn’t put in top-notch security; even the example repos I used say that, but it’s secure-enough 🤫).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing I did this weekend was redo this site. I wanted to make the &quot;About Me&quot; and &quot;Around Town&quot; pages more user-friendly. I wanted to rethink who my audience of this site is… besides me and my mom. I realized that I wanted it to be easier for prospective employers to see information about me. So reading about my favorite books and TV shows, while debatably interesting, maybe isn’t the best content for my &quot;About Me&quot; page. Instead, that should be my resume page. And then my &quot;Around Town&quot; page should look less bulletpoint-y and more section-y. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://brianm.me/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@BrianMitchL’s personal page&lt;/a&gt; as inspiration for what types of things I should be putting on mine. I still think that mine pales in comparison to his, but it’s closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh… I also purchased my domain! 🙌🏼. I had been hesitant to make the commitment of which domain to buy for a while (which is silly because I commit for a year when I sign my apartment contract annually), but I finally took the plunge and purchased my domain: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emmasax4.info&lt;/code&gt;. Technically, I could’ve swapped out &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.info&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emmasax4&lt;/code&gt; for just plain &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emmasax&lt;/code&gt;. But after a week of pondering what I wanted to choose, I realized that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;4&lt;/code&gt; is kind of my thing. My email has a 4. My Twitter has a 4. My GitHub has a 4. And of course, I did that all intentionally when I made those usernames (actually the email thing was just because &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emma.sax@gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; was already taken, and the rest came &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the email). So I figured that I might as well be intentional about my 4’s and just make it happen with that! So in one night, I went through the work of setting up my DNS, hooking it all up into GitHub, and by the time I went to bed, I had my own websites hosted on GitHub Pages with custom domains and SSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my website &quot;spike&quot;, I’d like to say that I learned a lot more about Jekyll. I learned more about how the Jekyll themes use CSS, I learned that a Jekyll theme is really just a bunch of CSS, and Jekyll itself is really just about the data structures and config files. I learned more about how the permalinks work. And I learned that Jekyll isn’t really that magic 🎉… I could make my own Jekyll site by adding one file at a time, instead of selecting a specific theme in GitHub’s Settings page. I learned more about DNS, and about hosting websites on custom domains. After all of this, I feel like I’m finally ready to take on the website world!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-11-05-more-websites-jekyll-and-dns/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-11-05-more-websites-jekyll-and-dns/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skimp and Splurge</title>
        
          <subtitle>Part 1: The Art of Saving Money</subtitle>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was initially written in December of 2016, even if I’m publishing it in 2019. In a way, it was my first attempt at a blog post (just not on this blog). So, I thought it’d be interesting to document it here. Since writing this, some amount of my opinions on these ideas have changed a little bit. Stay tuned for an updated list coming soon 😉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There comes a point in most young adults’ lives where they need to think about saving money. Whether they just graduated from college, just bought their first car, or are trying to save for a special occasion, it’s important to understand that money doesn’t grow on trees. There’s rarely a way for an average, middle-class 20-something-year-old to afford everything they’d like to have and have a reasonable savings account, too. Therefore, it’s up to the person to decide how they’d like to spend their money. Which usually involves a mixture of, what I call, &quot;skimping&quot; on things and &quot;splurging&quot; on things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s 10 things my list of &quot;skimps&quot; and &quot;splurges&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-skimp-daily-coffee&quot;&gt;1. SKIMP: daily coffee&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I don’t drink any coffee at all. Call me lucky that I don’t need the pick-me-up of energy in the morning, but because of it, I can easily save $150 a month from frequent trips to Starbucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-splurge-apartment-rent&quot;&gt;2. SPLURGE: apartment rent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though apartments provide a low-contract living situation, I like knowing that the place I’m living in is decently nice, in a good neighborhood, and I would feel comfortable living there for years to come if I wanted to. And it’s not like I was super picky. In fact, my requirement for living there included 6 things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Central heat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air conditioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dishwasher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Underground parking available&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free laundry (does not necessarily mean in-unit washer/dryer)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fitness room in building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-skimp-tons-of-new-clothes&quot;&gt;3. SKIMP: tons of new clothes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call it luck that at my job, jeans and t-shirts are totally appropriate, but I never am willing to spend more than about $30 on a shirt or a pair of pants if I don’t have to. Stay away from the designer stores and expensive retail stores. I only buy expensive clothes when I know I’ll be wearing them to a very important occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-splurge-eating-at-nice-restaurants&quot;&gt;4. SPLURGE: eating at nice restaurants&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean super pricey restaurants, just ones that aren’t fast-food chains. I would never skip on going out to eat with an old friend at a decently nice restaurant. Worst case scenario, I’m fed with good-tasting food, my wallet is $45 lighter, and I’ve gotten some socializing done with friend(s). Could be worse. And I’ll probably get leftovers out of it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-skimp-tons-of-takeout-and-fast-food&quot;&gt;5. SKIMP: tons of takeout and fast-food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it doesn’t seem like much, a month’s worth of take out fees and fast-food adds up. I’d much rather cook one meal, and have it and its leftovers last me three days than spend $5-10 every two days on lunches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-splurge-netflix&quot;&gt;6. SPLURGE: Netflix&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course everyone will have different opinions about this, but for me, Netflix is a necessity. Almost right up there with internet. For me, Netflix can easily occupy 3 hours worth of time, and it is a good distraction from the rest of your life when you just need a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-skimp-expensive-phone-bills-with-tons-of-unused-data&quot;&gt;7. SKIMP: expensive phone bills with tons of unused data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan on getting Internet and WiFi at your apartment, like most people have, then you can skip on the data a little bit. For me, 5GB is plenty for the occasional watching of videos and browsing the web. But to each their own (some people use over 10GB a month, and I know that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-splurge-a-good-car&quot;&gt;8. SPLURGE: a good car&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, my car was not cheap. I got a brand new Honda CR-V, with only 11 miles on it. The reason I got this car was because I think of it like an investment. If I bought a cheap car with 120,000 miles on it and it needed maintenance and new parts, then I spend the original amount on the car, plus gas, insurance, the maintenance, and parts. And, it could only last me 2-3 more years. But, if I buy a nice car that isn’t old and doesn’t need a lot of work, assuming I take proper care of the car, it could potentially last me 7 more years. And, I love my car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-skimp-buying-a-couch-right-when-i-move-out&quot;&gt;9. SKIMP: buying a couch right when I move out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, when you first move out, there are some things you need. Some pots and pans, and a shower curtain fall under that list. There are also some things you don’t need right away. A couch and a TV are in that list. Couches are expensive. Besides the bed/mattress and the dining table/chairs, it’ll be in the top 5 most expensive things you’ll buy for quite a while (at least in terms of furniture). Therefore, skip the couch. If you’re a college student, you’re probably used to lying on your bed watching cute animal videos anyway, so you’ll do just fine without a couch if you wait a couple months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-splurge-a-good-bed&quot;&gt;10. SPLURGE: a good bed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing with mattresses is, the better quality mattress you buy, the longer it’ll last, the more comfortable it’ll be, and the better you’ll sleep. And hopefully you’ll learn sometime in your adult life that sleeping is never something you should skimp on if you can help it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I hope this list might help you as you begin to budget, make real money  for yourself, and figure out how you want to live your financial life. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/skimp-and-splurge/2019-10-19-the-art-of-saving-money/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/skimp-and-splurge/2019-10-19-the-art-of-saving-money/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Time with Two Jobs</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago, after I started working full-time, I thought about pursuing a second job. Perhaps something in retail or serving. I eventually decided not to go through with that—I really didn’t need the additional money, since I work full-time as a software engineer. But this past January, I decided to make a change and take a second job anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons why a person might decide to get a second (or third) job is usually related to money. If a person is having trouble paying the bills with their first job, they may get another one to cover the difference. But for me, I didn’t necessarily &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a second job, I just &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; one. Since I had decided to do my Kenya vacation in August (read more about that &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/welcome-to-kenya/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), I figured that my savings account was going to take a significant hit if I didn’t make up some of that money through another job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-instacart&quot;&gt;Working with &lt;a href=&quot;https://shoppers.instacart.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instacart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;full-service-shopper&quot;&gt;Full-Service Shopper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my friends works a second job at Instacart as a full-service shopper/deliverer. She really enjoys it, too. She gets off her 9–5 job, and then drives around to different grocery stores, shops, uses an Instacart-provided debit card to pay, and then delivers the groceries to customers. She gets paid based on each order (what Instacart calls a &quot;batch&quot;), and she receives tips. Some of the deliveries are at apartment buildings, and some are at houses. The idea of shopping for food without spending any of &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; money appealed to me. So in late January, I applied to work as a full-service shopper for Instacart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first day on the job was really cold. This past winter, Minnesota had three days of extreme cold (think like –40°F). So my first day of working there was during one of these days. That first day involved a fair amount of delivery. On one of my orders, the customer had inputted the wrong address to deliver to, so the app tried to get me to drive 0 miles &lt;em&gt;back&lt;/em&gt; to the store to deliver the groceries instead of the customer’s home. I ended up having to submit a reimbursement request and call the &quot;Shopper Happiness&quot; line to get a refund for that. Another order had the bags packed so heavy by an in-store shopper that at least two of the seven bags broke on their way to the door to the apartment complex. I had to stop and pick up spilled yogurt, milk, and orange juice on the freezing cold sidewalk. And another order on that day involved delivering to an apartment complex that included four flights of stairs—and the stairs were outside. After that first day, I’m not really sure why I wanted to keep doing full-service delivery… but yet I signed up for the next few shifts and I kept doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked a variety of different regions/zones, including West Metro (Chanhassen, Shakopee, Eden Prairie, etc), Maple Grove (Maple Grove, Plymouth, Robbinsdale, Brooklyn Center, etc), and Minneapolis (Minneapolis, St. Louis Park, Golden Valley, etc). What I found was that the West Metro and the Maple Grove zones have the most driving involved. I remember once when I drove down to Shakopee to pick up a few bags for delivery, and then ended up driving all the way to Mound for the delivery. Approximately one hour of driving total, for just $15. If I don’t want to drive as much, then I should take up shifts in the Minneapolis zone. The square mileage is less in the Minneapolis zone, so there’s significantly less driving. However, there’s clearly more traffic. I’ve done several deliveries that were in downtown Minneapolis. Having to drive downtown, sometimes during rush hour traffic, park in congested lots at grocery stores, and then find a place to park on the street (that doesn’t cost money) so that you can run inside to deliver the groceries…… not particularly enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delivering in different zones also has different types of delivery locations. There’s a lot more apartment buildings in the Minneapolis zone, including at the university campus. This can be bad because sometimes the customer will want you to walk all of the groceries to their apartment door. So you need to ring the building, wait to be let up, find the elevator (or just take the stairs), and then walk through the maze of the hallway until you find the right door number. If the customer doesn’t answer to let you into the building, you need to sit there and wait for 10 minutes, and then call Shopper Happiness. One time this happened where I called about five times myself, and then had to call Shopper Happiness, who managed to contact the customer. When asked if the customer received any calls from me, they just said: &quot;I’ve been here the whole time, but I never heard anything else.&quot; The only thought going through my head was &quot;I’m not paid hourly… I’m paid by batch. So by wasting 40 minutes standing here waiting for you, I lost another potential $15&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delivering in suburb zones has less apartment buildings which is nice. Houses are easier to find and locate. And if the customer doesn’t answer the door, you can leave the groceries on the front step, and go back to your car to keep warm. However, I had to deliver to several houses where the customer didn’t snowplow their driveway, or didn’t do it well. Although that’s not a huge deal in terms of parking the car, dragging the groceries to the front door can be difficult if the walkways are snow and ice covered. I’m just amazed that I only fell once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to mention that I banged my car up a couple times, and later paid to fix that, too. So even though we’re paid per order, and we’re paid mileage (from each grocery store to each delivery location, but NOT from a delivery location to the next grocery store), there was still a decent amount of wear-and-tear on my car. In one month of delivery driving, I drove 1,255.3 miles, and that’s just working Instacart! I still drove to my 9–5 job each day, to run errands, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I do want to make it clear that there were a few awesome batches. One of mine, that started as a bad one (hot deli food and about 80 pounds of cat litter), turned out to be a good one. The customer that answered the door was super nice. He told me that he doesn’t leave his house at all, so he gets all of his groceries delivered to his door. Very pleasant, and it was clear he was very grateful. He also gave me a nice tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another order took an unexpected turn when I kept all of the groceries. The food was decent, but when I went to deliver, the customer never came to pick up the order. I messaged the customer in my app, called the customer, stood there for 30 minutes, and nothing. When I called Shopper Happiness, they told me that the original store I bought the groceries from had closed for the night, so I couldn’t return the items. So I could &quot;dispose of them how I choose to&quot;. So… I kept the groceries. Since I’m vegetarian, I gave the meat items to my friend (the same one who got me started with Instacart), and I kept everything else that appealed to me. I think maybe we got about $70 of free groceries that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple apartment complexes that I went to multiple times, too (generally homes for the elderly). I’ve been to so many places around the western half of the Twin Cities that sometimes I’ll even vaguely recognize a neighborhood, streets, or an area of town. There have been instances where my partner is driving, and we’re going to place I’ve never been to before in Burnsville. But yet, I recognize many of the streets we’re driving on, and I know that there’s a HyVee nearby. Even though I only have been in that area once or twice before, when you’re looking for a specific turn, you get used to the neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after about a month, I started to get a bit sick of it… as you can probably imagine from my description of Instacart delivery. The weather was still pretty bad, traffic was bad, especially during rush hour, and I found that I wasn’t a big fan of delivering to people. This was also made worse by the fact that only 50% of my customers would actually tip. It was also tiring. One week, I worked 29 hours. That’s in addition to the 40 hour work-week I had worked at my full-time job. Other weeks, I worked between 16–24 hours at Instacart. I’d get home at 2pm after working 6 hours of Instacart on a Saturday, and I’d have to take a nap, much to my partner’s dismay. I was putting so much time and energy into Instacart that it was affecting the rest of my life. So, in mid-March, I decided to switch from a full-service shopper to an in-store shopper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-store-shopper&quot;&gt;In-Store Shopper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are pros and cons of being an in-store shopper versus a full-service shopper. In-store shoppers are paid an hourly rate of $14. They’re technically employees, so they pay taxes straight out of their paycheck. They are scheduled on a weekly basis based on provided availability. They have bosses. They can be fired, and Instacart can give them rules and requirements they must follow. In-store shoppers also cannot deny a batch they receive. Full-service shoppers choose their own hours every week, and can pick up or drop hours without much prior notice. They are contractors, meaning they don’t pay any taxes on their paycheck, and instead get the full amount every pay week. However, that backfires when at tax season, the contractor then has to pay the same taxes, plus the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/self-employment-tax-social-security-and-medicare-taxes#targetText=The%20self-employment%20tax%20rate,for%20Medicare%20(hospital%20insurance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-employment tax&lt;/a&gt;.). Full-service shoppers don’t have a dress code, and they can shop as fast or as slowly as they like. When I worked, they could also decline batches if it involved too much driving, was too heavy, involved store(s) they didn’t like, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The promise of not having to drive and getting &quot;steady&quot; pay enticed me. My car had gotten a beating when I was working full-service, and I was sick of driving all over the west suburbs in the cold, snowy, and icey weather (yes, I know that summer would eventually come, but that’d be shortly followed by another winter). Some other benefits of working in-store would be that I’d no longer need to back and forth between different outdoor and indoor temperatures, and if there was a spare moment where I didn’t have a batch, at least I’d be sitting and relaxing inside, instead of in a running car. Also… the amount of times I had to go to the bathroom, but I had to hold it because there was no nearby bathroom 🚽😬…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched to in-store shopping, I got to select which store I wanted to work at. I decided to work at a Cub Foods that was right in between my full-time job and my home. This made it easy to get there when I was coming from home, and easy to get there when I was leaving straight from my normal day job. They provided me with a t-shirt (eventually I got three t-shirts), a new lanyard, and walked me through the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I noticed was that having to wait until a computer-generated schedule came out was sometimes not fun. You don’t know when you’re planning to work the next week, and you get assigned hours based on availability, but if there’s too many shoppers, then nobody gets the amount of hours they want. Sometimes when I requested 16 hours, I’d get assigned 8. Sometimes when I set myself to be available for 20, I’d get all 20, even if I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; only wanted 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, having so many rules wasn’t always fun. They had speed goals, so we’d have to strive to shop for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; amount of items in a certain amount of seconds (maybe around say 65 seconds per item). So that means if you have a three item order, you have to complete it in 3 minutes 15 seconds… yeah it’s not really possible to shop for, select, and go through checkout for three items in 3 minutes. But yet, that was the goal. The speeds of all of your batches are averaged, so one slow batch doesn’t throw everything off, but if you get a lot of small or time-heavy batches (think meat/deli counter, hard-to-find items, long checkout lines, etc), then your whole average will get skewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, despite these complaints, the job started out as really fun. I got to socialize, talk to other workers, and get to know more people. In spare time, I could occasionally read a magazine at the store, or finish up my own personal shopping during a break. The store had something called &quot;Sunday Funday&quot;, where the boss would buy the workers some snacks or cakes to eat during the shift. And, I was making the extra money I needed without doing much extra driving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of money, the biggest difference I found can be summarized like this: if you want to earn the most money as quickly as possible and don’t mind driving, then full-service is your thing; if you don’t want to drive, and you don’t mind earning money more slowly, then in-store may work best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked as an in-store shopper for several months. By mid-August (my trip was happening in August), I began to realize that I was almost done working Instacart. I was beginning to get tired of shopping for people and doing their chores. Some customers would be petty with me. Instacart started rolling out more rules around complete vs. incomplete deliveries. They lowered the speed goal. They decided to require all shoppers to use single bags instead of double bags (which means more bags per order). Other coworkers of mine weren’t getting the amount of hours they needed/wanted. And most importantly, my health was starting to be affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was eating out food so much more than before. I was spending money buying frozen meals for dinner instead of cooking food in my own home. I didn’t have the time that I needed to get proper sleep each night, and I wasn’t really getting any exercise. Also, I found that I wasn’t taking the time that I needed to properly practice self-care. I worked between 45–65 hours a week for eight months, so I was burning myself out. Lastly, I felt like Instacart had sort of taken over my life; I was always thinking about Instacart, worrying about my performance, stressing out over schedules, etc. Given the fact that it doesn’t give me a huge ratio of my income, it seemed like the stress it was causing me wasn’t worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So one month after returning from Kenya, I worked my last shift as an Instacart in-store shopper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learned&quot;&gt;What I Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard for me to summarize what I’ve learned during this, but I’ll do my best:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to work more than 40 hours a week. I admire anybody that works more than 40 hours a week for any consistent amount of time. Oh, and nobody working that much should be struggling to pay their bills.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People that are paid hourly are not lazy or unintelligent (I already knew this, but it was confirmed).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working physical jobs are super difficult (I sit on a computer at my full-time job).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People have a second job for a variety of different reasons—don’t go thinking you know everyone else’s reasons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tipping is super important! People rely on tips to help make their living and earn a decent amount of money (I already knew this, too, but it was also confirmed). Every delivery person (eg: pizza delivery workers, Bite Squad deliverers, furniture deliverers, etc) deserve to get tipped, especially if they’re using their own personal car to do the deliveries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can’t expect your deliverers to be able to read your mind. You’ve got to give them strict instructions about directions, what foods to pick out, what to substitute with, etc, otherwise you’ve just gotta understand that they don’t know exactly what you want because THEY’RE NOT YOU.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re getting a service or item delivered to you, you should either be there to receive it, or you should tell them they can just drop it off. It’s actually pretty rude to ask for delivery between the hours of 5–6pm and then just not be there or not answer the door. Considering each driver then has to wait for you to arrive… yeah you totally just disrespected that person’s time and money (delivery people are people, too).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The gig economy doesn’t always pay their contractors fairly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any person that uses their car for their work should be tipped kindly and paid fairly for that mileage and gas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And most importantly: people that work part-time are people, too. And they don’t deserve to be blamed, yelled at, or their pay to be docked for just doing their best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I finished working with Instacart, I earned approximately an extra ~$5,700. However, I ran into the conundrum where even though I intended to save that money for my trip to Kenya, I just ended up spending additional money as well as my Kenya trip. The more money I made, the more I felt entitled to spend. But at the end of the day, I’m so grateful for the opportunity to work the second job to help bolster my savings account. Because of Instacart, I was able to fund a once-in-a-lifetime vacation without really denting my savings account. I managed to meet new friends, get to socialize, and most importantly, have new experiences and new knowledge about the working economy and society in the U.S. But if I’m completely honest, I’m not sure I’ll work a second job if I can help it ever again. Burnout at work is real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: I did keep detailed records of the miles I drove, the money I made, the hours I worked, and the batches I completed if you’re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-10-18-my-time-with-two-jobs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://emmasax4.info//blog/posts/2019-10-18-my-time-with-two-jobs/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
